

Contact

Phone

+49 (0)1577 350 52 02

Email

merayo.rafa@gmail.com

Address

Frankfurt am Main. Willing to relocate

Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/rafaelmerayo/

Github

https://github.com/RafaMR

Expertise

- JavaScript (ES6) | React
- HTML 5 | CSS | Bootstrap
- NodeJS | ExpressJS
- Mongo Db | Axios
- Git | Github

Languages

Spanish - Native

English - Full profesional proficiency

German - Full profesional proficiency

Rafael Merayo

Full Stack Developer with a background in Sales

Full Stack Developer with a background in Sales and 10+ years of experience as a Sales Manager at online tech companies looking forward to changing careers and joining a project to put into practice my technical skills and work experience acquired.

Experience

O January 2022 - August 2022

Student. Web development Bootcamp. Ironhack.

- Six months part-time immersive course to become a Full Stack Developer.
- Learned Front-end design and Back-end architecture fundamentals, using top-notch technologies such as JavaScript, React, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, NodeJs, ExpressJs, MongoDb, Axios, Git and Github.
- Developed a total of three projects including:
- **Videogame-Elon-Mars:** https://elon-mars.netlify.app Positioned this video game on Product Hunt as the 5th product of the day on 18/04/2022.
- Meetech.com: https://meetech-app.herokuapp.com
 Networking app to look for tech events.
- Ironpump.com: https://ironpump.netlify.app Fitness app to manage your own workouts.

November 2015 - Present

Sales Manager Spain. eGENTIC. Frankfrut am Main.

- eGENTIC is the world leader in online lead generation offering companies qualified consumer leads generated through Online Sweepstakes and Email Marketing.
- Responsible for the new business acquisition and account management of top-tier clients in the Spanish market from the following verticals: Call centres, Finance, Telco, Insurance, NGO, Energy, Education and E-commerce.
- Helped to position Spain as the second top market in EMEA by increasing the annual team revenue on average by +9,3% and overachieving on average +35% of personal annual sales goals of 720k€/year. Team yearly revenue exceeding € 4 million.

March 2012 - October 2015

Sales Manager Spain Whisbi. (Google external contractor). Barcelona

- Whisbi worked on behalf of Google in Spain helping digital marketing agencies to acquire new business on AdWords (Google Partners Program).
- Responsible for a portfolio of 50 to 60 agencies contributing to an +7,8% increase in AdWords average investment by increasing +38% of new business acquired by the agencies (AdWords accounts).

October 2009 - March 2012

Other sales positions include:

- Sales Manager Spain ReviewPro: Software management tool for the hotel industry.
- Account Manager Mirai: Web design and Digital Marketing for the hotel industry.

Education

O October 2006 - March 2009

Diplomatura Turismo. BA in Hospitality management.

Universidad Autónoma de Madrid. University degree. 180 ECTS.